
  
const europeQuestions = [
    {question: 'If you were to visit the town of Sintra, which country would you go?', answer: 'Portugal'},
    {question: 'While on a boat, you must dock at the Piraeus, which country should you be?', answer: 'Greece'},
    {question: 'Your flight you drop you at the Schiphol Airport. Which country will you land?', answer: 'The Netherlands'},
    {question: 'You will explore some of the Basque provinces. Which of these countries will you go?', answer: 'Spain'},
    {question: 'You will visit a country famous for its banks and watches? Which country will you go?', answer: 'Switzerland'},
    {question: 'You will taste the original Budweiser Budvar in its brewery. Which country will you go?',answer: 'Czech Republic'},
    {question: 'You may be able to see for yourself Mr. Dracula in Transylvania. Which country will you go?', answer: 'Romania'},
    {question: 'Why dont you visit the largest city in Europe â€“ that spans to Asia too. Where should you go?', answer: 'Turkey'},
    {question: 'You can go to the birthplace of french-fries and have good beer too. Which country will you go?', answer: 'Belgium'},
    {question: 'You can get to see the remains of the most famous wall of the modern age. Where will you go?', answer: 'Germany'},
    {question: 'You visit the place where the tie was invented (maybe to regret the fact).Where would you go?', answer: 'Croatia'},
    {question: 'You may greet the original Santa Klaus there in his homeland. Where will you go?', answer:'Finland'},
    {question: 'You can try some of the world\'s most renowned meatballs', answer: 'Sweden'},
    {question: 'You can visit the country that is the home of the world\'s most famous queen. Where will you go?', answer: 'United Kindgom'},
];
const europeanCountries = ['Austria', 'Belgium', 'Bulgaria', 'Croacia', 'Cyprus', 'Czech Republic', 'Denmark', 'Estonia', 'Finland', 'France', 'Germany', 'Greece', 'Hungary', 'Ireland', 'Italy', 'Latvia', 'Lithuania', 'Luxembourg', 'Malta', 'The Netherlands', 'Poland', 'Portugal', 'Romania', 'Slovakia', 'Slovenia', 'Spain', 'Sweden', 'United Kingdom', 'United Kingdom'];
function randomIntergerUpto(max){
    return Math.floor(Math.random() * (max + 1) );
}

function getRandomQuestions(){
    let questionIndexes = [];
    while ( questionIndexes.length<4 ){
    const randomIndex = randomIntergerUpto(europeQuestions.length-1)
    if (!questionIndexes.includes(randomIndex)){
        questionIndexes.push(randomIndex);
    }
}
console.log(questionIndexes);
const randomQuestions = [];
for (let i =0; i<questionIndexes.length; i++){
    randomQuestions.push(
        europeQuestions[questionIndexes[i]]
    );
    }
    return randomQuestions;
}

//select question element
const questionToGuessElement = document.querySelector('.selected-question');
//select boxes
const countryOptionsElements = document.querySelectorAll('.answer-box');

let correctCountryIndex;


function startRound(){

    const randomQuestions = getRandomQuestions();

    correctCountryIndex = randomIntergerUpto(3);

    const questionNumber = displayQuestionNumber();

    //randomly select one of the selected questions
    const selectedQuestion = randomQuestions[correctCountryIndex].question;
    //display selected question
    questionToGuessElement.innerHTML = selectedQuestion;
    //display random country's names in the boxes
    for (let i = 0; i<countryOptionsElements.length; i++){
        const country = randomQuestions[i];
        const countryOptionsElement = countryOptionsElements[i];
        countryOptionsElement.innerHTML = country.answer;
    }
    //take out selected question of the array
    europeQuestions.splice(randomQuestions[correctCountryIndex], 1);

}
startRound();
//check if clicked element corresponds to the right answer
const evaluateRightAnswer = document.querySelector('.display-answer');

function answerClick(event){
    const button = event.target;
    const clickedIndex = Number(button.getAttribute('data-index'));
    if(clickedIndex === correctCountryIndex) {
        evaluateRightAnswer.innerHTML = 'Cooool. You have conquered it!';
        evaluateRightAnswer.style.backgroundColor = 'rgba(255,255,255, 0.7)';
        setTimeout(newRound(), 250);
    } else {
        evaluateRightAnswer.innerHTML = 'You should travel around more';
        evaluateRightAnswer.style.backgroundColor = 'rgba(255,255,255, 0.7)';
        newRound();
        setTimeout(newRound(), 250);
    }
console.log(europeQuestions.splice());
}
for (let i = 0; i < countryOptionsElements.length; i++){
    const countryOptionsElement = countryOptionsElements[i];
    countryOptionsElement.addEventListener('click', 
        answerClick
        );
}



//Restart game next question
function newRound() {
    //remove selected question
    questionToGuessElement.innerHTML= '';
    console.log(questionToGuessElement);

    // //remove countries from boxes
    for (let i = 0; i < countryOptionsElements.length; i++){
    countryOptionsElements[i].innerHTML= '';
    }
    console.log(countryOptionsElements);
    startRound();
}

//next question - not working

// const buttonNext = document.querySelector('.next-question');
// buttonNext.addEventListener('click', newRound);
// buttonNext.onclick = newRound();
//
//change question number - not working
function displayQuestionNumber(){
    let number = 1;
    const questionNumber = document.querySelector('.question-count-number');
    while (number < 10){
    questionNumber.innnerHTML = `${number}`;
    number++;
    }
}
//run game until round 10 and score
let score = 0;